A Guide to the Caveats entered from the Virginia Land Office, 1782-1923
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Caveats entered from the Virginia Land Office, 1782-1923
The Library of Virginia
LOI 54
4.95 cu ft (11 boxes)
Virginia. Land Office.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession LOI 54 transferred by the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1948.
Historical Information
The act which established the previous Land Office passed the General Assembly on 22 June 1779. The register was the head of the Office and was appointed by joint ballot of both houses of the legislature.
Scope and Content
Papers pertaining to caveats entered in the Land Office. In addition to notices of caveats entered, the papers include copies of surveys, warrants, explanations regarding the entry of caveats, and decisions in the cases. The papers cover the years between 1782 and 1923, with some years missing. The caveats were also indexed chronologically; see LOI 55.
Index Terms
corporate Names:
Virginia. Land Office.
Subjects:
Land Grants -- Virginia.; Surveying -- Virginia.
Genre and Form Terms:
State government records -- Virginia.
Contents List
- Caveats entered from the Virginia Land Office, 1782-1923., Extent: 11 boxes (4.95 cu. ft.). (Box 1-11)
  Chronological
  - Caveats, entered 1782. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1783. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered January-June 1784. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered July-December 1784. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered January-May 1785. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered June-September 1785. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered October-December 1785. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered January-June 1786. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered July-December 1786. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1787. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1788. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1789. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1790. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1791. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1792. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered 1793. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1794. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1795. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1796. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1797. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1798. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Caveats, entered 1799. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Caveats, entered 1800. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Caveats, entered 1801. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Caveats, entered 1802. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1803. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered 1804. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1805. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1806. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1807. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1808. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1809. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Caveats, entered 1810. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Caveats, entered 1811. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Caveats, entered 1812. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Caveats, entered 1813. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1814. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered 1815. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1816. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1817. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1818. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1819. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1820. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Caveats, entered 1821. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Caveats, entered 1822. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Caveats, entered 1823. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Caveats, entered 1824. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Caveats, entered 1825. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Caveats, entered 1826. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Caveats, entered 1827. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Caveats, entered 1828. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Caveats, entered 1829. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Caveats, entered 1830. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Caveats, entered 1831. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Caveats, entered 1832. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Caveats, entered 1833. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Caveats, entered 1834. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Caveats, entered 1835. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Caveats, entered 1836. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1837. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered January-June 1838. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered August-December 1838. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1839. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1840. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1841. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered January-November 1842. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Caveats, entered December 1842. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Caveats, entered 1843. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Caveats, entered 1844. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Caveats, entered 1845. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Caveats, entered 1846. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Caveats, entered 1847. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1848. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered January-August 1849. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered September-December 1849. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered January-August 1850. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered September-December 1850. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1851. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1852. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1853. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered January-July 1854. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered August-December 1854. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered January-May 1855. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered June-December 1855. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1856. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered January-June 1857. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered July-December 1857. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered 1858. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1859. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1860. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1861. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1862. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1863. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Caveats, entered 1865. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Caveats, entered 1867. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Caveats, entered 1868. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Caveats, entered 1869. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Caveats, entered 1870. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Caveats, entered 1871. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Caveats, entered 1871. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Caveats, entered 1873. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Caveats, entered 1874. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Caveats, entered 1875. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1876. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered 1877. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1878. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Caveats, entered 1880. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Caveats, entered 1881. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Caveats, entered 1882. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Caveats, entered 1883. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Caveats, entered 1884. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Caveats, entered 1885. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Caveats, entered 1887. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Caveats, entered 1888. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Caveats, entered 1889. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Caveats, entered 1890. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Caveats, entered 1891. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Caveats, entered 1893. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Caveats, entered 1895. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Caveats, entered 1896. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Caveats, entered 1900. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Caveats, entered 1901. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Caveats, entered 1903. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Caveats, entered 1904. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Caveats, entered 1905. (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Caveats, entered 1906. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Caveats, entered 1907. (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Caveats, entered 1911. (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Caveats, entered 1912. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Caveats, entered 1913. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Caveats, entered 1916. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Caveats, entered 1917. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Caveats, entered 1920. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Caveats, entered 1923. (Box 11, Folder 4)